# **Cameron Cooper**

■ cameron.w.cooper@gmail.com 

□ 7199008036 

■ www.linkedin.com/in/cameronwc 

■ https://cameron.cooper.co

#### **SUMMARY**

Results focused Security Engineer with 5 years experience conducting security reviews, developing applications, and hacking. In my most recent position I worked as a Senior Security Engineer leading the CVS Health/Aetna Health Security Operations team where I supported over 3000 engineers and maintained security for all CVS Health/Aetna Health products.

#### EXPERIENCE

# Senior Security Engineer CVS Health/Aetna Health

2020 - Present

- Lead Security Engineer for CVS and Aetna Health Security Operations.
- Created integrations, maintained, and administrated: Datatheorem, OWASP Zap, Checkmarx CxSAST, Prisma Cloud Compute (Twistlock), NexusIQ, Snyk, and Github Advanced Security Suite.
- Built a system for all security tools to be easily configured and managed under a single React application.
- Facilitated Security Reviews, False Positive Reviews, and remediation of security issues.
- Created and maintained secure by default docker images for use downstream in applications.
- Created security automation microservices in python, nodejs, and go.
- · Guided over 3000 engineers on docker, python, security, CI/CD, architecture, best practices, reviews, and audits.
- Built, debugged, maintained, and improved ci pipelines/circleci orbs in Jenkins and Circleci.
- Built and integrated a SIEM (ELK) into the Aetna infrastructure.
- Facilitated technical interviews for DevSecOps engineers and Software Security Analysts.
- Collaborated with Governance, Risk, and Management (GRC) to define, implement, and remain in compliance with security controls including controls governed by HIPPA and PCI-DSS.
- Led procurement, testing, and integration of new security products.

## Full Stack Software Engineer

Parsons 2019 - 2020

- · Worked with a clearance on microservices and ETL pipelines for multiple sects of the military.
- Created scalable object recognition microservices for images and videos with Darknet and YOLO.
- Wrote/tested RESTful services with Java and Spring.
- Updated and improved AngularJS front-end applications.
- Scanned and remediated vulnerabilities in our applications with Fortify Static Code Analysis (SAST).
- Developed an automated test suite with Postman/Newman.
- Designed Cloud Data Enrichment pipelines.
- · Transformed Natural Language Processing, Data Enrichment, and Import/Export pipelines to production code.

# Founder / Software Engineer

Formulated, LLC 2017 - Present

- Improved client lead generation conversion rate by 79% that improved revenue by \$300k
- Created Full Stack Web Applications for small businesses that converted leads into customers
- · Contracted by companies to do security reviews, penetration testing, and audits
- Created maintainable and scalable CI/CD pipelines for timely and secure updates

# **PROJECTS**

# Home Server

2019 - Present

- Manage a 30TB Unraid virtualization server/NAS/docker registry for over 40 users.
- Services include: Bitwarden, Nextcloud, Home Assistant, daily offsite backups to Backblaze, reverse proxy, status pages, game servers, over 30+ docker images.
- Maintained under the coop.ninja domain.
- 99.9% Uptime.

#### Pixel Helper

2019 - Present

- Pixel Helper is a simple open source image aggregator for use in design.
- · Created after I found issues with sourcing royalty free high quality images to use as placeholders or in my final designs.
- Technologies: ReactJS, Github Actions, Heroku, Snyk.

#### **Deauthentication Detector**

2019 - 2019

- Worked with a peer to create a deauthentication packet detection device.
- Using a Raspberry pi this device detects a deauthentication packet sent across a network and attempts to find information on the source.
- Coded with Python3, Node, MongoDB, Bash and Aircrack-ng.

#### **EDUCATION**

### Bachelor's of Science in Computer Security

University of Colorado Colorado Springs • Colorado Springs, CO • 2019

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

#### Certified Ethical Hacker

EC-Council • In Progress

Advanced Web Developer Bootcamp

Udemy • 2018

AngularJS & NodeJS Bootcamp

Udemy • 2018

Modern React with Redux Bootcamp

Udemy • 2018

Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp

Udemy • 2017

#### **SKILLS**

SAST: Checkmarx, Fortify, Github Advanced Security Suite

DAST: OWASP Zap, Data Theorem

SCA: Snyk, Nexus IQ, Github Advanced Security Suite

Container Security: Snyk, Twistlock

CI/CD: CircleCI, Jenkins, Github Actions

Container: Docker, Docker-Compose

AWS: Elastic Beanstalk, Secret Manager, EC2, Elastic Container Registry, Lambda, IAM, dynamoDB, s3, RDS, VPC,

Route 53

Python: openCV, Django, Flask

Ruby: Ruby on Rails

Java: Spring

NodeJS: React

Databases: MySQL, PostgresQL, MariaDB, MongoDB

Registries: Nexus Repo, Artifactory, Elastic Container Registry

NIST, OWASP Top 10, CWE Top 25

HIPPA, PCI DSS

**Linux Administration** 

**Terraform**